Inventory of the Edward Bartlett Lee papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Edward Bartlett Lee papers
1897-1939
XX242
Hoover Institution Archives
7 manuscript boxes, 1 card file box, 1 oversize folder (3.2 linear feet)
Correspondence, leaflets, pamphlets, posters, clippings, photographs, and postcards relating to the activities of various relief organizations during and immediately after World War I and to the Liberty Loan drives and other aspects of the war effort in the United States.
Lee, Edward Bartlett.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
American business executive; National War Savings Committee publicity worker during World War I.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, leaflets, pamphlets, posters, clippings, photographs, and postcards relating to the activities of various relief organizations during and immediately after World War I and to the Liberty Loan drives and other aspects of the war effort in the United States.
International relief.; World War, 1914-1918--Civilian relief.; World War, 1914-1918--United States.
- War Savings Committee publications, drafts to editor, 1918 (Box-folder 1: 1-2)
- War Fund propaganda, requests for aid, 1915-1918 (Box-folder 1: 3)
- Womens' War Effort, American Red Cross, pamphlets and correspondence, 1916-1918 (Box-folder 1: 4)
- International Red Cross, pamphlets, 1916-1917 (Box-folder 1: 5)
- The Smileage Advertiser (Military Entertainment publication), 1918 (Box-folder 1: 6)
- Tobacco Fund, 1919 (Box-folder 1: 7)
- British Red Cross, auction catalogue, 1915 (Box-folder 1: 8)
- Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA), 1917-1918 (Box-folder 1: 9)
- War Relief Clearing House, 1915-1918 (Box-folder 1: 10)
- General correspondence, 1918 (Box-folder 1: 11)
- Newspaper clippings, undated (Box-folder 2: 1)
- War Savings Committee, correspondence, 1918 (Box-folder 2: 2)
- American Committee for Armenian and Syrian Relief, 1916-1917 (Box-folder 2: 3)
- Western European Aid, pamphlets and propaganda, 1915-1920 (Box-folder 2: 4)
- European Relief, pamphlets and correspondence, 1915-1918 (Box-folder 2: 5-6)
- Electric Bond and Share Company, correspondence, 1916-1918 (Box-folder 2: 7)
- University correspondence, 1918 (Box-folder 2: 8)
- European Relief, pamphlets, 1916-1919 (Box-folder 2: 9)
- European (French) Relief, pamphlets, 1916-1919 (Box-folder 2: 10)
- Memorabilia, undated (Box-folder 2: 11)
- Recruiting posters, 1915-1919 (Box-folder 3: 1)
- Recruiting posters, correspondence, wartime entertainment, 1916-1919 (Box-folder 3: 2, Map case)
- Liberty Loans, 1917 (Box-folder 3: 3)
- Liberty Loans, pamphlets, 1917 (Box-folder 3: 4)
- Liberty Loans, pamphlets, 1916-1919 (Box-folder 3: 5)
- Liberty Loan Committee of 1917, 1917-1919 (Box-folder 3: 6)
- Aid Committees, 1920 (Box-folder 3: 7)
- Programs, 1915-1920 (Box-folder 4: 1)
- Political propaganda, 1917-1919 (Box-folder 4: 2)
- Post-war pamphlets, 1917-1919 (Box-folder 4: 3)
- Programs and pamphlets, 1915-1917 (Box-folder 4: 4)
- Boycott on German-made goods, 1918 (Box-folder 4: 5)
- War Savings Committee publications, correspondence, 1914-1918 (Box-folder 4: 6)
- War Savings Committee publications, correspondence, 1918 (Box-folder 4: 7)
- Personal correspondence, 1915-1917 (Box-folder 5: 1)
- Postcards, war correspondence, 1915-1918 (Box-folder 5: 2)
- Liberty Loans, Victory Bonds, 1915-1919 (Box-folder 5: 3)
- Liberty Loans, Victory Bonds, 1915-1919 (Box-folder 5: 4)
- German goods boycott, American Defense Society, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 5: 5)
- Correspondence, 1913-1917 (Box-folder 5: 6)
- Correspondence and memorabilia, 1916-1919 (Box-folder 6: 1)
- War Funds and stamps, propaganda, 1914-1918 (Box-folder 6: 2)
- War Funds and stamps, propaganda, 1914-1918 (Box-folder 6: 3)
- War Savings Committee, 1917-1919 (Box-folder 6: 4)
- National Security League, 1914-1919 (Box-folder 6: 5-6)
- Catalogues, 1897-1918 (Box-folder 7: 1)
- Leagues and Societies, pamphlets and correspondence, 1917-1918 (Box-folder 7: 3)
- Propaganda news clippings, undated (Box-folder 7: 4)
- War Preparedness Societies, 1916-1918 (Box-folder 7: 5)
- Incremental materials (Box 8)